# **AURELIE JOSSERAND**

Front-End Software Engineer

Front-end developer and multidisciplinary designer currently based in Washington D.C.

Over ten years of experience in delivering products for companies, businesses and government entities around the globe with a focus on design, usability, accessibility and inclusivity.

#### CONTACT

josserand.n.aurelie@gmail.com (405) 503-7341

Pronouns: She / They

# **TOOLBOX**

HTML5

CSS

JavaScript

React Github

**Figma** 

Google Workspace Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Indesign

Adobe Premiere Pro

3DSMAX Lumion Sketchup

Revit Dynamo

AutoCAD

## **LANGUAGES**

English - Fluent French - Native Spanish - Beginner

## **OTHER QUALIFICATIONS**

Registered Architect
EDAC Accredited
LEED Accredited
LEED Accredited BD+C

## **Green Card Holder**

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Codecademy - Front End Engineer Track

Winter 2021 to Present

- Created an interactive tip calculator app that helps users calculate tip based on percentage and number of people using HTML, CSS, and JS React.
- Second project.
- Third project

# SmithGroup, Washington, District of Columbia

2015 to present - Project Architect

- Leads system coordination on large scale projects involving multi-disciplinary teams of engineers and designers.
- Involved in all project phases from project pursuits to construction administration.
- Promotes the company brand through online and in person community activities and organization involvement.

# Miles Associates, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

2012 to 2015 - Project Coordinator

- Developed the company Website Design using Squarespace CMS.
- Led 3D visualizations efforts.
- Assisted project teams on construction documentation.

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Smithgroup - Technology in Practice Group

Summer 2017 to present - Digital Delivery Champion

• Identifies and Implements automation processes and BIM standards.

# Academy of Architecture for Health

2017 to 2020 - FTP & Logistics Lead Member

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK

Spring 2011 to Summer 2012

Bachelor of Architecture, NAAB Professional Degree

## Ecole Nationale Superieure d'Architecture, France

Fall 2007 to Fall 2010

Bachelor of Architecture, Non-Professional Degree

# **AWARD**

Summer Leadership Summit - Next Generation Scholar Recipient

Summer Leadership Summit 2017